Thread Waxing Space (Gallery)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Program Files, 1980s-2001, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-38; 35.7 linear feet)
  - "Conceptual Art as Neurobiological Praxis," Curated by Warren Neidich (Mar. 25 - May 1, 1999) (Box 29)
    - Neidich Contract, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Budget, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Shipping, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Returned Shipping Forms, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Returns, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Artist Interview, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Fundraising, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Listings, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Artist Book, circa 1999 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Press, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Neidich Bio, 1997-1999 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Slides of Works in Show, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Uta Barth, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - Sam Durant, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - Eric Duyckaerts, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - Spencer Finch, 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Carl Fudge, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - Rainer Ganahl, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - Liam Gillick, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - Bios and Background Information, circa 1999 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - Panel Listings, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - Press Release, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - Douglas Gordon, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 57)
    - Jason Rhoades, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 58)
    - Grennan & Sperandio, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - Cocktail Reception, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - Loan Forms, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 62)
    - Notes, circa 1998-1999 (Box 29, Folder 63)
  - "Conceptual Art as Neurobiological Praxis," Curated by Warren Neidich (Mar. 25 - May 1, 1999) (Box 30)
    - Ricci Albenda, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Beom Kim, circa 1999 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Anne Kugler, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Ann Lislegaard, circa 1999 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - T. Kelly Mason, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Jack Pierson, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Matthew Ritchie, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Andrea Robbins, circa 1999 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Jonathan Horowitz, 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Thomas Ruff, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Charline von Heyl, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Elin Wikstrom, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Photographic Materials, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - "Dragons on the Wall: A Work in Progress" (May 2, 13-15, 1999), circa 1994-1999, (15 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 30, Folder 14-28)
  - Threads of History (May 26 - June 19, 1999), 1999, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 29-30)
  - "After the Gold Rush," Curated by Lia Gangitano and Joseph Wolin (May 26 - July 1, 1999) (Box 30)
    - Deinstallation, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Performances, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Kaucyila Brooke, 1996-1999 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Anthony Burdin, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Mark Grotjahn, 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Shane Hassett, 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Cameron Jamie, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Clifford LeCuyer, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - Susan Lutz, 1997-1999 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Georgia Metz, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Yunhee Min, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Dave Muller, 1997-1999 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - Kori Newkirk, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - Elizabeth Saveri, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - Ruben Ortiz Torres, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Shirley Tse, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - Pae White, 1995, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - General Information, 1996-1999 (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - Trip to L.A., 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - L.A. Performers, 1997-1999 (Box 30, Folder 50)
    - Press, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 51)
    - Announcement Cards, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 52)
    - Press Release, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 53)
    - Listings, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 54)
    - L.A. Signage, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 55)
    - L.A. Show ArtForum Ad, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 56)
    - Anthony DiMaggio Review, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 57)
    - Loan Forms, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 58)
    - Checklist, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 59)
    - Hunter's File, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 60)
    - Rejects - L.A., 1999 (Box 30, Folder 61)
    - Shipping Forms for Returns, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 62)
  - "After the Gold Rush," Curated by Lia Gangitano and Joseph Wolin (May 26 - July 1, 1999) (Box 31)
    - Photographic Materials, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Dave Muller and Anthony Burdin, "Scum Invasion" (May 26 - July 1, 1999), 1999 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Scout," Curated by Eileen Myles (June 2, 1999), 1998-1999 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - School of Visual Arts Graduate Thesis Exhibition (July 17-30, 1999), 1999 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - "My Eye Hurts," Curated by David Mackintosh (Sept. 12, 1999), 1996-1999, (6 folders; includes 2 sound discs: 45rpm vinyl and CD) (Box 31, Folder 5-10)
  - Jimmy Raskin, "Why must we draw the tightrope walker this way?" (Sept. 14, 1999), 1999, (3 folders) (Box 31, Folder 11-13)
  - Time Out Student Guide Internship Article ["Foul Play" and Jimmy Raskin Printing] (Fall 1999), 1999 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - CMJ Fall Music Festival (Sept. 15-18, 1999), 1999, (3 folders) (Box 31, Folder 15-17)
  - "Foul Play," Curated by Cheryl Kaplan and Asia Ingalls (Sept. 30 - Nov. 20, 1999) (Box 31)
    - Administrative File, 1999-2000, (3 folders) (Box 31, Folder 18-20)
    - Shipping, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Completed Loan Forms, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Matthew Antezzo, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Ida Applebroog, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Beth B, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Erica Baum, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Anne Gardiner, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Victor Burgin, 1999, (Includes 1 computer disc: ZIP) (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Anthony James, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Proposal, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Jun Iseyama, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Birgit Jurgenssen and Catherine Opie, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Michelle Lopez, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Catherine Opie, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Fabio Mauri, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Andrea Pesendorfer, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Carol Rama, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Blake Rayne, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - Nigel Rolfe, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Jeff Wall, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - Collier Schorr, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - Lawrence Weiner, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - Contemporary Visual Arts Preview, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 43)
    - Press, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Press Release, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - Budget, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - Checklist, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 47)
    - General Information, 1997-1999, (Includes 1 computer disc: ZIP) (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - Jeff Wall Condition Report, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 49)
  - Photographic Materials for "Foul Play" and "Apeshit v3" (Sept. 30 - Nov. 20, 1999), 1999 (Box 31, Folder 50)
  - Leah Gilliam, "Apeshit v3" (Sept. 30 - Nov. 20, 1999), 1999-2000, (7 folders) (Box 31, Folder 51-57)
  - Ruth Verde Zein, "Brasilia Dream" (Oct. 3, 1999), 1999 (Box 31, Folder 58)
  - "Scout," Curated by Eileen Myles (Nov. 2, 1999), 1999 (Box 31, Folder 59)
  - "Scout," Curated by Eileen Myles (Nov. 2, 1999, Feb. 16, 2000, May 30, 2000), 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 60)
  - Reclame (Nov. 18, 1999), 1999 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Jeri Cain Rossi, "Red Wine Moan" (Nov. 23, 1999), 1999, (Includes 1 sound cassette) (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn Art Museum Response to Mayor Guliani, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Boaz Barkan, "Symptoms of Origin: A Chain of Dances" (Dec. 1999 - Apr. 2000), 1999-2001, (9 folders; includes 1 computer disc: ZIP) (Box 32, Folder 4-12)
  - "Mr. Fascination," Curated by Lia Gangitano (Dec. 2, 1999 - Jan. 15, 2000) (Box 32)
    - Trans> Catalog, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - General Information, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Photographic Materials, 1998-1999 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Listings, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Checklist, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Administrative File, circa 1999-2001 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Press, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Panel, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Shipping, 1999-2000 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Film, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Ellen Cantor, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Erik Hanson, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Ineborg Lusher (Ying-bo), 1999 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Loan Forms, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - James Dawson Hollis, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Dana Hoey, 1997, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Sharon Lockhart, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Robert Marshall, 1998-circa 1999 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Joshua Smith, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Dan Torop, circa 1999 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Jochen Klein, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Suara Welitoff, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Virginia Nimarkoh, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Martin Gustavsson, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Alexei Hay and Justine Parsons, 1999 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Maura Jasper, "Karaoke Project" (Dec. 2, 1999 - Jan. 15, 2000), 1999-2000, (6 folders) (Box 32, Folder 38-43)
  - Phillip Virus, "The Virus Has Been Spread" (Jan. 20-22, 2000), 1996-2000, (5 folders; includes 1 sound disc: CD, and 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 32, Folder 44-48)
  - Alex Rivera, "Tijuana 2000 AD," Curated by Erika Dalya Muhammad [Proposal], 1998-1999 (Box 32, Folder 49)
  - Gregory Coates, "To Be Distributed" (Feb. 1 - Mar. 4, 2000), 1994-2000, (3 folders) (Box 32, Folder 50-52)
  - Gregory Coates, "To Be Distributed" and Sheila Pepe, "Josephine" (Feb. 1 - Mar. 4, 2000), 2000, (4 folders) (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Sheila Pepe, "Josephine" (Feb. 1 - Mar. 4, 2000), 1999-2000, (3 folders) (Box 33, Folder 5-7)
  - "Scout," Curated by Eileen Myles (Feb. 16, 2000), 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Art For All Ages (Mar. 8, 2000), circa 2000 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Steve Reinke, Curated by Tom Folland and Josephine Wolin (Mar. 10-12, 2000), 2000, (4 folders) (Box 33, Folder 10-13)
  - "Achieving Failure: Gym Culture 2000," Curated by Bill Arning (Mar. 24 - Apr. 29, 2000) (Box 33)
    - Returned Loan Forms, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 2000, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 15-16)
    - Linda Nishio, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Gabriel Martinez, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Elizabeth Stephens, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Cleveland-NY Returns, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - Kopp & Kordansky Claim, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Tom Cole, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - Installation Instructions, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - Shipping, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Cleveland, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 26)
    - Video, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 27)
    - Cleveland Loan Addendums, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 28)
    - Artists Bios, circa 2000 (Box 33, Folder 29)
    - Benefit, Ted, Inc. Contract, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 30)
    - Let Me Hear Your Body Talk Benefit, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 31)
    - Benefit Committee, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 32)
    - Loan Addendums, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 33)
    - Crunch Loan Forms, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 34)
    - Bill Arning/Joel Sanders Bios, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 35)
    - Tour, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 36)
    - Press, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 37)
    - Printed Materials, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - Tour/Press Slides, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - Completed Loan Form/Invites To Be Sent Out, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - Discussions at The New School, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - Catalog, 1999-2000, (Includes 1 computer disc: 3.5") (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - George Spencer, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - Press Release, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - Contacts, 1999 (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - Slides, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - Digital Print Color Copies, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Do Something (May 10, 2000), 2000 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - "Catherine Opie: Large Format Polaroids" (May 12 - June 10, 2000), 1999-2000, (4 folders) (Box 33, Folder 49-52)
  - "Catherine Opie: Large Format Polaroids" (May 12 - June 10, 2000), 1999-2000, (10 folders; includes 2 sound cassettes) (Box 34, Folder 1-10)
  - Marc Strauss Reading [Proposal], 2000 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - "Our Wandering Thoughts" (June 13-24, 2000), 2000, (5 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 34, Folder 12-16)
  - Expanded Art Ideas (June 13-24, 2000), 2000, (2 folders; includes 1 computer disc: ZIP) (Box 34, Folder 17-18)
  - Verner Panton Exhibition [Proposed], 1998-2000 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Yaddo Centennial Celebration, John Kelly, "Chronicles of a Performance Artist" (June 15, 2000), circa 2000, (1 sound cassette) (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Yaddo Centennial Celebration, William Pope L., "Eracism" (June 15, 2000), 2000, (2 folders; includes 1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 34, Folder 21-22)
  - Yaddo Centennial Celebration, Miscellaneous (June 15, 2000), 1999-2000 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - "The Life Casts of Cynthia Plaster Caster" (June 28 - July 29, 2000), 2000, (8 folders; includes 1 computer disc: 3.5") (Box 34, Folder 24-31)
  - School of Visual Arts (Aug. 7-23, 2000), 2000 (Box 34, Folder 32)
  - Borre Saethre, "Module for Mood" (Sept. 9 - Oct. 12, 2000), 2000 (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - "Lovett/Codagnone: Play" (Sept. 9 - Oct. 12, 2000), 2000 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - "Scout," Curated by Eileen Myles (Oct. 3, 2000), 2000 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - CMJ Fall Music Festival (Oct. 19-22, 2000), 2000 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - "Death Race 2000," Slides (Dec. 2, 2000 - Jan. 13, 2001), 2000-2001 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - "Research Architecture" (Feb. 9 - Mar. 17, 2001), 2001 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Sigalit Landau (May 3 - June 9, 2001), 2001 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Post-IZUM Moods Music Series, Video Recordings, 1993, (12 videocassettes: Hi8 from Box 6, Folder 9) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Post-IZUM Moods Music Series, Video Recordings, 1993, (19 videocassettes: Hi8 from Box 6, Folder 10) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Restricted Folders, (13 folders) (Box 37 (hol), Folder 1-13)
  - "Beyond Ars Medica: Treasures from the Mutter Museum," Oversized Support Material (Nov. 19, 1995 - Jan. 11, 1996), 1994-1996, (Oversized materials from Box 14, Folder 19) (Box 38 (sol), Folder 1)
  - "Beyond Ars Medica: Treasures from the Mutter Museum," Press (Nov. 19, 1995 - Jan. 11, 1996), 1995-1996, (Oversized materials from Box 14, Folder 21) (Box 38 (sol), Folder 2)
  - "Ascent of Western Civilization," Curated by Michael Azerrad, [Exhibition Materials?] (Sept. 13 - Nov. 1, 1997), 1980s-1990s, (Oversized materials from Box 21, Folder 19) (Box 38 (sol), Folder 3)
  - Little Red School House Benefit and Exhibition, Posters (Nov. 13-16, 1997),1997, (Oversized materials from Box 22, Folder 20) (Box 38 (sol), Folder 4)
- Research Files, 1993-2000, Series 2:; (Box 35; 8 folders)
  Research Files contains a handful of folders housing materials such as artists' biographies, photographs, slides, scattered correspondence, and printed materials about artists and exhibitions. In some cases the gallery appears to have compiled the information, while in other cases it appears that the artist has sent information to the gallery.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by last name; general research is filed at the end of the series.
  - Bamber, Judie, mid-1990s (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Castronova, Joseph, circa 1998 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Kelly, John, 2000 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Majoli, Monica, 1993-1995 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Mayerson, Keith, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Peyton, Elizabeth, circa 1997 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Rapson, Sarah, 1998 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Paintings/Artist Research, 1995-1998 (Box 35, Folder 12)
- Press Files, 1991-circa 2001, Series 3:; (Boxes 35, 38; 0.4 linear feet)
  This series includes press books and a handful of newspaper clippings about the art world. The press book materials were originally housed in plastic sleeves in binders, but were removed for preservation. The order of the press book materials was retained.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - All Press for Thread Waxing Space and Tim Nye (1992-1999), 1994-1999 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - ArtForum Magazine With Letters Cut Out of Pages, 1999, (Oversized material housed in Box 38, Folder 5) (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Brochures for Thread Waxing Space, 1992, 1996 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1999-2000 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Press Book (Sept. 1991 - May 1994), 1991-circa 1999, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 17-18)
  - Press Book (May 1994 - Archigram), 1994-circa 1999 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Press Book (Aug. 1998 - Present), 1998-circa 2001 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Selected Press for Thread Waxing Space (1993-1999), 1998-circa 1999 (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - Women's Action Coalition Logo, 1990s (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - ArtForum Magazine With Letters Cut Out of Pages, 1999, (Oversized material from Box 35, Folder 14) (Box 38 (sol), Folder 5)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1989-1993, undated, Series 4:; (Boxes 35-36; 0.6 linear feet)
  Found are sound cassettes and videocassette recordings, most of which are unique recordings. The recordings are likely related to programs found in Program Files; however, based on the existing labels the processing archivist was unable to integrate with certainty the materials into the Program Files series. The materials were not viewed and verified by the processing archivist.
  Video recordings are arranged first, followed by sound recordings. Folders are arranged chronologically, with undated materials filed first.
  - Jon Hassel (#2), Richard Horowitz (#3), Jaron Lanier (#4), undated, (3 videocassettes: VHS) (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Richard Horowitz, Rockefeller, undated, (1 videocassette: VHS) (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - Unlabeled Videocassettes, undated, (2 folders; 5 videocassettes: 4 VHS and 1 Hi8) (Box 35, Folder 25-26)
  - Sound Recordings, 1989-circa 1993, undated, (11 sound cassettes housed in Shoebox 3) (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Dave Soldier: Selections for Susan James, undated (1 sound cassette)
    Terraces, E. Lurie, undated (1 sound cassette)
    Peter Whitney, Bell Trees, undated (1 sound cassette)
    Zorn, For Your Eyes Only, undated (1 sound cassette)
    "A Decade of Debris: Music for Homemade Instruments," 1989 (1 sound cassette)
    Ken Butler Live (5/30/1993), 1993 (1 sound cassette)
    Tom Hamilton, 1993 (1 sound cassette)
    Fode Kowyate, circa 1993 (1 sound cassette)
    Ruth Schonthal, Manhattan Chamber Orchestra, circa 1993 (1 sound cassette)
    Unlabeled Sound Cassettes, undated (2 sound cassettes)